[环境音]
[Ambient sound]
張培贊: 小人那天六馬回來，剛走到花園，就聽見小姐跟姑爺在說話。
Zhang Peizan: Yes, I came back from walking the horses that day. Just when I walked to the garden, I heard the young lady and her fiancé talking.
張培贊: 約姑爺半夜到花園來取黃金，是小人一時貪心。
Zhang Peizan: She asked him to come to the garden in the middle of the night to get gold. Feelings of greed stirred in my heart at that moment.
[戲曲演奏]
[Opera orchestra plays]
和聲 [唱]: 他説道爲貪黃金去偷釵，在園外悄悄等候雪春來，
♪ Chorus (singing): He said that he stole a hairpin because he was greedy for gold, and quietly waited outside the garden for Xuechun. ♪
[戲曲演奏]
[Opera orchestra plays]
和聲 [唱]: 拍掌三聲門兒開，交釵換銀無阻礙。
♪ Chorus (singing): He clapped his hands three times so that the gate would open, and he could exchange the hairpin for money without any hindrance. ♪
[戲曲演奏]
[Opera orchestra plays]
雪春: 林姑爺，你千萬別辜負了小姐一番好意。
Xuechun: Mr. Lin, you must not let my lady’s kindness go to waste.
雪春: 時候不早了，請回吧。
Xuechun: It's getting late, please go back.
[戲曲演奏]
[Opera orchestra plays]
和聲 [唱]: 心慌意亂腳顫抖，摔到地上把事敗。
♪ Chorus (singing): Flustered, legs trembling, he fell to the ground and ruined his plan. ♪
雪春: 林姑爺?
Xuechun: Mr. Lin?
[音效：惊呼]
[Sound effect: Gasp]
和聲: 雪春識破大聲叫。
Chorus: Xuechun recognized who it was and shouted loudly.
雪春: 啊，是你!
Xuechun: Ah, it’s you!
張培贊: 不許嚷，你要嚷我就要你的命。
Zhang Peizan: Don't shout. If you shout, I will kill you.
和聲 [唱]: 一失手害她芳魂赴陰台。
♪ Chorus (singing): One mistake of his caused her soul to travel to the underworld. ♪
雪春: 救命啊！救命啊！
Xuechun: Help! Help!
[音乐停止]
[Music stops]
張培贊: 我剛藏好兇刀和金子，就看見姑爺來了，就做了我的替死鬼了。
Zhang Peizan: I saw Lin coming over just when I managed to hide the knife and the gold. So, he became my scapegoat!